Hello Gas, today our topic is a little different. Today
our plan is insurance, but
health is not included in insurance because it is
also health and it is a very basic need. There are
many types of travel insurance that you do overseas. Travel
insurance is very good in that
if you are going abroad for a trip
or if you are planning any
trip that is
outside India, then any health
insurance gives you domestic health. 99% of the
cases are such where all the health insurances are
domestic. Some companies'
plans give you 1% international health insurance.
But if you are planning something outside
and most of the time you should definitely get your travel
insurance. Your
travel outside India and whatever your
convenience is, it does something. So let's
start today with the travel agency that
offers it. We will only talk about
why travel insurance is necessary and what are its
basic fundamentals. We will talk about this,
which will give you an answer. If you
purchase travel insurance, then you will get an idea
that you
can finalize this policy, then no matter which travel company you are
travelling to.
My insurance gets stolen, society etc.,
my passport etc. or if I
go overseas and have any health condition
issue, there is a lot of issues, there are a lot of cases, in a
lot of cases,
someone dies, then the
entire transportation from there, all these
things are included in our health
insurance, okay, and
many companies also provide these,
like HDFC, Care,
many companies which
also provide driver insurance, now let's talk about this,
I have told you
why there is a need for it, similarly what happens, it is
not mandatory in many countries, it is
mandatory
in most of the companies, nowadays you send health and
travel insurance along with the visa,
this is mandatory and by taking this
you are benefited, there is no loss, whatever
financial losses you have, they will be borne entirely by
you,
so first of all, if you are
purchasing a travel insurance, then there will be
two things in it, one will be yours,
including that and Canada, so you should understand that
inclusion and a little bit about Canada  The premium is
going to be higher compared to
excluding that and Canada, so excluding
that and including Canada, it is a
little cheaper, okay, and its
price totally depends
on your number of days, there is also a 360-day plan, I will
also talk about the plan type,
before that let me tell you that whatever is
calculated for this depends on your journey, for
how many days are you going,
what is the start date, which country are you going to
and what is the return date,
your premium is calculated on that only,
okay, you can take this policy individually, you can take a
floater, you can take a floater,
you can also take this policy for multiple trips for as many members, you
can also take one air policy as per multiple trips, if you are travelling abroad frequently then you can
also take a multi-trip policy and Student Explore Plan,
if you have gone abroad on a student visa for
study purposes then also you can purchase it, so
these plans were included in this, which
I am telling you, all these plans are included in
this policy.  And this is
very important, it has become a basic need if
you are going on a foreign trip, then this is a very
important thing. First of all, let us talk about
what all things are there in this too because
if you are taking a health, then you
see the plane, there is no need to see so much in this, there are
two-three points which you have to pick up, you have to see
with the company, first of all you have to check
your generation, is the company imposing a
waiting period on my free accessories, since
when is it doing this, is there any waiting
period or not, the first point is great and
this should be discussed with the company, secondly, if
you are purchasing any travel insurance,
then it is very less in Indian EB,
if you are going abroad, for example, you are getting an insurance of
₹5 lakh, 10 lakh dollars,
then you should take it in that EB only
and it will be shown on the website in that EB only,
when you calculate the premium, it will
show $5 for so many days and this is
my amount, that will be your premium,
okay, let's talk, there is in-
patient care in this too, that means in-patient
hospital  It means that in this also you have
hospitalization for more than 24 hours,
now the company gives you evening injury
in this thing also as per the condition of health, it is
also there in this, okay, let me talk about the second thing,
hospital expenses, there are all kinds of taxes here,
whatever hospitals there are,
they have taxes, we need to check whether
we have OPD tax or not, whether we are getting
daily alarm or not, whether we are getting it
in ambulance, so
which all the iron ambulance services are we getting,
like all this, we need to
check in the browser of the plan,
inside the policy, apart from that, if I talk about dental
expenses, that means we are getting it,
we also check all those things
inside the policy, okay, apart from this, as
I talk about, apart from this, there is personal
accident tax, so
how much is the personal accident tax and if there is, then
how many dollars is it,
you will definitely check that, it will be written in all your plan details, so in a
normal way, you will
check all the things, after that you will calculate and
then you will purchase, the premium will
not be much if
Your policy will cost within Rs. 65000, I am giving you an
approximate idea and if you are
going for a very short time as an individual then it is
given around Indian Rupees
but including that Canada, in comparison to this it will be a
little expensive, if there is
no expense then yours
is fine, so when I
made a video on travel insurance for you, I
thought it right because there was a lot of demand from
people going abroad, so I
made this video specifically for those people, what all
things you can see in your policy, what all things
are mandated, so I am showing you all these things on the side,
follow all these things, you will get a good plane,
purchase it and comfortably enjoy your
overseas planning, thank you
[Music]